# Ryan Weiler

### Senior Underwriting Associate



(860) 839-3975

ryanweiler92@gmail.com

Senior Underwriting Associate with over 5 years of successful experience in underwriting and claims operations. Recognized consistently for performance excellence and contributions to success in the insurance industry. Strengths in strategic vision and creative thinking backed by training in Organizational Communication.



#### **Skills**

Strategic Vision

Creative Thinking

Pattern Recognition

Internal/External Communication

Medical/Insurance Terminology

Research





# **Work History**

Aetna, Hartford, CT

- Analyzed medical and pharmacy claim utilization and ongoing risks while partnering with internal marketing and external brokers to deliver competitive proposals.
- Managed new business prospects by identifying, evaluating, and assessing risk to achieve company revenue and membership goals.
- Assisted members of our team while serving as subject matter expert on case installation process to ensure that sold cases were properly implemented.

#### Senior Pend/Adjustment Commercial Claims

ConnectiCare Inc., Farmington, CT

**Senior Underwriting Associate** 

- Payment integrity research responsibility including potential fraud by member or provider
- Review, research and resolve participating provider-initiated appeals and correspondence
- Assist parent company, EmblemHealth, with the review and resolution of

2019-01 - Current

2015-06 - 2018-12

2013-04 - 2015-06

non-participating provider and member-initiated grievances

 Act as a knowledge resource for fellow specialists and other departments.

#### Senior Event Technician/Manager

Central Connecticut State University, New Britain, CT Management of 50 student employees in various areas of Event Management. Working closely with and on and off campus clients to plan events, and manage the student employment budget.



# **Education**

2011-09 - 2015-05

#### **Bachelor of Arts: Organizational Communication**

Central Connecticut State University - New Britain, CT

- Lambda Pi Eta Communication Honor Society
- Researched, conducted focus groups, administered surveys and analyzed data for social media use of student athletes to create a social media policy for client Thomas Pincince, Assistant Athletic Director of CCSU
- Graduated with 3.62 GPA
- Minored in Geography



# **Community & Country**

